Danielle Ussery

Full Stack Web Developer / Graphic Designer

Riverside, CA 92507 revelationdesigner@gmail.com 3109083989

Motivated Designer and Full Stack Developer with 9 years of experience creating custom graphic components and web pages with the use of Adobe software, React, and MySQL databases. Strong creative and analytical skills. Adept in various coding languages and debugging. Background in MERN development style and user-centered conceptualization.

Web Portfolio: https://portfolium.com/danielleussery/portfolio

Graphic Portfolio: https://www.revelationdesigns.net

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Graphic Designer

Ultra Pro International LLC - Commerce, CA October 2018 to Present

- Drive the creative direction of campaigns, with an understanding of typography, layout and art direction
- Liaising effectively with clients and other team members
- Artwork sublimation with a high aptitude for color theory
- Meet deadlines in high pressure environment while seeing projects through from inception to production
- · Maintain and improve design standards with the willingness to listen to feedback and use it to improve

Graphic/Web Designer

Glory Bound Missionary Baptist Church - Long Beach, CA September 2014 to November 2018

- Create weekly programs for services
- Manages the upkeep of the church website
- Create event posters and flyer
- Collaborating with the video department to upload content to the site

Design Manager - Business Development

Brandable - Los Angeles, CA

January 2018 to July 2018

- Conceptualizing and building brand identities based on influencer's needs
- Collaborating with marketing and creative teams to create eye-catching designs and engaging copy
- · Adjust designs based on feedback from clients, buyers, engineers, and consumer safety groups
- · Creating marketing materials including sales decks, social media graphics, photos, and videos
- Develop eye-catching, cost-effective and safe packaging for products
- Point of sale (POS) displays
- Retouching product and lifestyle photos
- Project Management staying in touch with vendors, printing companies, & developers for all projects given

Technical: HTML, copywriting and editing, package die lines, and product renderings

Production Design Intern

Paper Decor More - Los Angeles, CA August 2016 to April 2018

- Design marketing material
- Create ideas for original craft classes
- Design greeting and event cards

Graphic Designer

2020AVE - Los Angeles, CA February 2017 to September 2017

- Designs email marketing campaigns and website page banners.
- Responsible for maintaining data of all email campaigns and delivering analyzed data presentations weekly.
- Maintains database of marketing contacts by segmenting the database by various demographics and psychographics.
- Updating site banners along with page and product links

Use of Software: Klaviyo, Shopify, Tawk, Google Analytics, and Adobe CS6 programs (Photoshop, Illustrator, Media Encoder, After Effects, Atom)

Technical: HTML, Split A/B Testing, Copywriting, and Marketing Strategies

Graphic Designer

Ohzone

October 2016 to August 2017

- Mock up logo designs for a start up company
- Creating UI buttons and app icons
- Providing user testing opinions to assist user functionality
- Creating low fidelity & high fidelity UI wireframes with page design options

Contract Graphic Designer

Bleu Brand Development - Santa Monica, CA December 2016 to January 2017

- Designed print ready product labels
- Created clientele food truck design

Use of Software: Adobe CC programs (Photoshop, Illustrator, Media Encoder, After Effects, InDesign)

Retail Associate

Macy's - Culver City, CA May 2016 to January 2017

- Organizing and tidying the stands in the sales floor
- Maintaining clean fitting rooms
- Knowledge of the items we sell and the best deals we have in the departments I work in
- Assisting customers with questions on sizes and fits of clothing

Retail Sales Consultant: Print Services

Office Depot - Culver City, CA March 2015 to March 2016

- Responsible for completing print service orders correctly and in a timely fashion
- Building lasting customer and associate relationships
- Operating printing equipment: color and b&w printers, laser printers, laminating machines, and binding machines (glue, spiral and comb)

Education

Associate Degree in Advanced Full Stack Web Development in Web Development

Bryan University - Tempe, AZ November 2021 to Present

Full Stack Web Development Certificate in Web Development

Bryan University - Tempe, AZ

November 2020 to November 2021

Bachelor of Science in Graphic & Web Design

The Art Institute of California-Argosy University Los Angeles - Santa Monica, CA July 2015 to December 2016

Associate of Science in Graphic Design

Art Institute of California-Argosy University Los Angeles - Santa Monica, CA August 2012 to June 2015

Skills

- Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Bridge and Acrobat (9 years)
- After Effects (Motion Graphics) (3 years)
- Word, Exel, PowerPoint (10+ years)
- CSS3, HTML 5 (9 years)
- Utilizes networking and organizational skills, has a sense of color, works collaboratively with others, and great multitask abilities. (5 years)
- Business Development (4 years)
- · Acrobat (9 years)
- Dreamweaver (4 years)
- Typography (9 years)
- Graphic Design (9 years)
- Print Production (5 years)
- Motion Graphics (2 years)
- Time Management (9 years)
- Adobe InDesign (9 years)
- Packaging (7 years)
- Adobe Photoshop (9 years)
- Adobe Illustrator (9 years)
- Data Entry (6 years)
- User Interface (UI)
- Copywriting (2 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- Email Marketing (2 years)
- Branding (9 years)
- Front-end development (4 years)
- PostgreSQL (Less than 1 year)
- MySQL (Less than 1 year)
- MongoDB (Less than 1 year)
- Mongoose (Less than 1 year)

- Docker (Less than 1 year)
- Apache (Less than 1 year)
- JSON (Less than 1 year)
- DOM (Less than 1 year)
- Express.js (Less than 1 year)
- React (1 year)
- Node.js (Less than 1 year)

Links

http://www.revelationdesigns.net/

https://portfolium.com/danielleussery/portfolio

Awards

Best Of Quarter

October 2012

I was awarded Best of Quarter for Type 1, Form and Space and Concept Design between 2012 and 2014.

Dean's Honor Roll

September 2015

Presented with the Dean's Honor Roll certificate for acquiring a GPA of a 3.85.

Best of Quarter

November 2016

I was awarded Best of Quarter in Design Team 2 for the project Santa Monica's New Heroes Celebration.

Oustanding Achievement Award

December 2016

Was awarded the Outstanding Achievement Award for my graduate portfolio.

Assessments

Graphic Design — Highly Proficient

November 2019

Using graphic design techniques and producing visual media to communicate concepts.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Graphic Design — **Expert**

October 2019

Using graphic design techniques and producing visual media to communicate concepts.

Full results: Expert

Graphic Design — Highly Proficient

July 2019

Using graphic design techniques and producing visual media to communicate concepts.

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Attention to Detail — Highly Proficient

July 2019

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting

information.

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Attention to detail — Highly Proficient

February 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Groups

AIGA

March 2014 to Present

I was the Vice President of the chapter at my campus March 2015 - May 2016 I was the Treasurer from Jan 2015 - March 2015

Alpha Beta Gamma

April 2014 to Present

I am apart of the Alpha Beta Gamma business honor society chapter at my campus.

I was the Lead Designer over a group of four from June 2015 - January 2016. I along with 3 other members designed e-mail flyers and posters.

I was also the Secretary from Jan 2015 - June 2015